<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Crypto on timonrieger.de</title>
    <link>https://timonrieger.de/tags/crypto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crypto on timonrieger.de</description>
    <image>
      <title>timonrieger.de</title>
      <url>https://timonrieger.de/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Timon Rieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 11:02:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://timonrieger.de/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Crypto Profits with This Bullrun Strategy</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/maximize-crypto-profits-with-this-bullrun-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/maximize-crypto-profits-with-this-bullrun-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post deals with trading the crypto bullruns in the most optimal way to secure profits using the CBB Index. This strategy would have easily outperformed holding bitcoin, as we would have sold at each cycle top and reinvested everything in the bear market. I will use this plan for altcoins as well, as they are highly correlated with bitcoin, making it difficult to predict the exact top for each coin. This approach may limit maximum profits, but it helps to secure them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backtesting a Crypto Trading Signals Group</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/5-backtesting-crypto-trading-signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/5-backtesting-crypto-trading-signals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into finance-related content on YouTube, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen all these ads where someone is making 20k a month with their crypto signals and that you should definitely join their Telegram group too. Although 99.9% of these groups are definitely scams and don&amp;rsquo;t work at all, I wanted to review how a select group has performed in the past. Note that this is not a public group, but a paid group that I will be backtesting. I got access to this group through my work colleague whose company has access to this group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
