<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on timonrieger.de</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on timonrieger.de</description>
    <image>
      <title>timonrieger.de</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Timon Rieger</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arkivr</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/arkivr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:28:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/arkivr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arkivr is an archiving software as a self-hostable web server that allows you to store and organize resources such as links, files and more for easy retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see my instance &lt;a href=&#34;https://arkivr.timonrieger.de&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/arkivr&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleagues and I have been saving interesting websites, documents and general learning resources in a Discord chat for months. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to add the links or files there, but finding a particular resource was cumbersome. So I quickly set up a minimal version with a simple Flask server and have been using it daily ever since. I really like the concept and my first implementation, so I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about scaling it from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/spa-mpa-or-a-hybrid-42fdf6b3415c&#34;&gt;multi-page to a single-page application&lt;/a&gt;, adding self-hosting capability with Docker, support files and much more functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Boiler Templates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/blog-boiler-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 16:35:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/blog-boiler-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blog Boiler is a set of two templates to get started with a free, easy and predesigned blog template that will help you get started blogging in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I switched my blog to Hugo I had been using the Pro template myself. You can find more detailed information about usage on Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/blog-boiler-pro&#34;&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/blog-boiler-lite&#34;&gt;Lite&lt;/a&gt; version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this project during the 100 Days of Code challenge. It was a long-term project spanning several days, implementing various features over time. While the design itself is not my own, I was drawn to the idea of having a self-hosted space where I could write about my ideas and thoughts. I continued developing it over time, adapting it to my needs.
Initially, it used JSON storage via &lt;a href=&#34;https://npoint.io/&#34;&gt;npoint&lt;/a&gt; for blog posts, which is still being used in the Lite version. Later, I enhanced the Pro version by adding a PostgreSQL database for blog posts to enable basic CRUD operations, along with features like tags, user management, and comments. I maintained my own instance of the Pro version running alongside the Lite and Pro templates for a while. Recently, I migrated the blog to Hugo and have since discontinued development and usage of this project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Nomad Society</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/air-nomad-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/air-nomad-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air Nomad Society is a free email service that sends subscribers the best flight deals based on their travel preferences on a weekly basis as an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can signup &lt;a href=&#34;https://ans.timonrieger.de&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and view the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/air-nomad-society&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for building this email service originally came from Dr. Angela Yu&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/course/100-days-of-code/&#34;&gt;100 Days of Code Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;, which basically started my whole journey into the world of software and programming. I think on day 35 of that course we started developing this flight service. The idea behind it was that you have a Google Sheet as a database replacement (back then we hadn&amp;rsquo;t talked about/learned how to interact with databases programmatically) and you get the countries listed in the file and you search for the best flights to those places and save the price back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crypticorn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/crypticorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 16:36:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/crypticorn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crypticorn is a software as a service (SaaS) that allows you to leverage the power of AI in the crypto space. We offer a range of services from price predictions to a automated crypto trading bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://crypticorn.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date with the latest developments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filmhub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/filmhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 16:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/filmhub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmhub is a platform for discovering and sharing movies. It is a web application that allows users to rank movies and share them with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/filmhub&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Coaches</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/human-coaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 16:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/human-coaches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human Coaches is a family business that I run together with my mother. We help students to improve their learning skills and offer tutoring. We also analyze people&amp;rsquo;s personalities according to the Human Design System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit our website &lt;a href=&#34;https://humancoaches.de&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
