<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>timonrieger.de</title>
    <link>https://timonrieger.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on timonrieger.de</description>
    <image>
      <title>timonrieger.de</title>
      <url>https://timonrieger.de/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.145.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Timon Rieger</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 11:03:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://timonrieger.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arkivr</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/projects/arkivr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 16:28:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/projects/arkivr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Arkivr is an archiving software as a self-hostable web server that allows you to store and organize resources such as links, files and more for easy retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see my instance &lt;a href=&#34;https://arkivr.timonrieger.de&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/arkivr&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleagues and I have been saving interesting websites, documents and general learning resources in a Discord chat for months. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to add the links or files there, but finding a particular resource was cumbersome. So I quickly set up a minimal version with a simple Flask server and have been using it daily ever since. I really like the concept and my first implementation, so I&amp;rsquo;m thinking about scaling it from a &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/swlh/spa-mpa-or-a-hybrid-42fdf6b3415c&#34;&gt;multi-page to a single-page application&lt;/a&gt;, adding self-hosting capability with Docker, support files and much more functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blog Boiler Templates</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/projects/blog-boiler-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 16:35:02 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/projects/blog-boiler-templates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blog Boiler is a set of two templates to get started with a free, easy and predesigned blog template that will help you get started blogging in minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I switched my blog to Hugo I had been using the Pro template myself. You can find more detailed information about usage on Github, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/blog-boiler-pro&#34;&gt;Pro&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/blog-boiler-lite&#34;&gt;Lite&lt;/a&gt; version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started this project during the 100 Days of Code challenge. It was a long-term project spanning several days, implementing various features over time. While the design itself is not my own, I was drawn to the idea of having a self-hosted space where I could write about my ideas and thoughts. I continued developing it over time, adapting it to my needs.
Initially, it used JSON storage via &lt;a href=&#34;https://npoint.io/&#34;&gt;npoint&lt;/a&gt; for blog posts, which is still being used in the Lite version. Later, I enhanced the Pro version by adding a PostgreSQL database for blog posts to enable basic CRUD operations, along with features like tags, user management, and comments. I maintained my own instance of the Pro version running alongside the Lite and Pro templates for a while. Recently, I migrated the blog to Hugo and have since discontinued development and usage of this project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air Nomad Society</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/air-nomad-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/air-nomad-society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air Nomad Society is a free email service that sends subscribers the best flight deals based on their travel preferences on a weekly basis as an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can signup &lt;a href=&#34;https://ans.timonrieger.de&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and view the source code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/air-nomad-society&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;intention&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason for building this email service originally came from Dr. Angela Yu&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/course/100-days-of-code/&#34;&gt;100 Days of Code Bootcamp&lt;/a&gt;, which basically started my whole journey into the world of software and programming. I think on day 35 of that course we started developing this flight service. The idea behind it was that you have a Google Sheet as a database replacement (back then we hadn&amp;rsquo;t talked about/learned how to interact with databases programmatically) and you get the countries listed in the file and you search for the best flights to those places and save the price back.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crypticorn</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/projects/crypticorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 16:36:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/projects/crypticorn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crypticorn is a software as a service (SaaS) that allows you to leverage the power of AI in the crypto space. We offer a range of services from price predictions to a automated crypto trading bot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://crypticorn.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to stay up to date with the latest developments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local AI Development for Free</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/local-ai-development-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 21:39:48 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/local-ai-development-for-free/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this short article, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to develop locally with LLMs, making AI development free and private. With the rising costs of AI services, running models locally is becoming an increasingly attractive option for developers who want full control over their AI development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Betting Strategy (2)</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/building-a-betting-strategy-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/building-a-betting-strategy-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while and the teams are already deep into the Bundesliga season. Nevertheless, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to deprive you of my findings of simulating the strategy. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/blog/building-a-betting-strategy-1/&#34;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at 14 seasons of Bundesliga data to analyze patterns in match results, goal times and odds trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;our-strategy&#34;&gt;Our Strategy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategy I will be backtesting today will be betting on over 0.5 goals in the 30th minute if until then no goal has been scored. At the time of writing the odds with these conditions average at around 1.2. The odds are crucial to the profitability of this strategy, so keep that in mind. I will walk you through my analysis and thoughts when writing the code for it. You can find the unfortunately unorganized notebook and the data for this study on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/website/blob/v2/assets/data/building-a-betting-strategy.zip&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Filmhub</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/projects/filmhub/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 16:42:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/projects/filmhub/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Filmhub is a platform for discovering and sharing movies. It is a web application that allows users to rank movies and share them with friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit the website &lt;a href=&#34;https://filmhub.timonrieger.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the code on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/timonrieger/filmhub&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximize Crypto Profits with This Bullrun Strategy</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/maximize-crypto-profits-with-this-bullrun-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/maximize-crypto-profits-with-this-bullrun-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This blog post deals with trading the crypto bullruns in the most optimal way to secure profits using the CBB Index. This strategy would have easily outperformed holding bitcoin, as we would have sold at each cycle top and reinvested everything in the bear market. I will use this plan for altcoins as well, as they are highly correlated with bitcoin, making it difficult to predict the exact top for each coin. This approach may limit maximum profits, but it helps to secure them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building a Betting Strategy (1)</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/building-a-betting-strategy-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/building-a-betting-strategy-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The European Football Championship is in full swing and, fittingly, I had the idea to develop a betting strategy for the upcoming Bundesliga season. Let´s analyze some historical data and develop a thesis. We will be using data from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.openligadb.de/&#34;&gt;OpenLigaDB&lt;/a&gt; from 2009/10 to 2023/24 and explore statistics like the distribution of match outcomes, results by winning team, and scoring times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, the data is processed and visualized using Python, Plotly and Matplotlib. Our aim is to uncover trends and patterns that will be useful for a follow-up post on value betting strategies, focusing specifically on bets on more than 0.5 goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backtesting a Crypto Trading Signals Group</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/5-backtesting-crypto-trading-signals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/5-backtesting-crypto-trading-signals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re into finance-related content on YouTube, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen all these ads where someone is making 20k a month with their crypto signals and that you should definitely join their Telegram group too. Although 99.9% of these groups are definitely scams and don&amp;rsquo;t work at all, I wanted to review how a select group has performed in the past. Note that this is not a public group, but a paid group that I will be backtesting. I got access to this group through my work colleague whose company has access to this group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Life and Emotions</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-emotions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-emotions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning about emotions and how to control them has been one of the best decisions I&amp;rsquo;ve made in recent years. The last post about Marcus Aurelius&amp;rsquo; meditations might plant some seeds for you in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Life and Ethics</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Meditations of Marcus Aurelius really brought me into the stoic philosophy. After the initial part &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-death&#34;&gt;about life and death&lt;/a&gt; below I&amp;rsquo;ll continue with quotes regarding &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-ethics&#34;&gt;about life and ethics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Life and Death</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-death/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/about-life-and-death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While reading the Meditations of Marcus Aurelius, I saved some passages using &lt;a href=&#34;https://readwise.io/i/timon41&#34;&gt;Readwise&lt;/a&gt; that I would like to share here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing 75 Years of LEGO</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/blog/analyzing-75-years-of-lego/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/blog/analyzing-75-years-of-lego/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-lego&#34;&gt;About Lego&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LEGO is a globally recognized brand of construction toys, known for its interlocking plastic bricks. The name &amp;ldquo;LEGO&amp;rdquo; comes from the Danish words &amp;ldquo;leg godt,&amp;rdquo; meaning &amp;ldquo;play well.&amp;rdquo; LEGO bricks are designed to be versatile and can be assembled and connected in countless ways, allowing children and adults alike to build various structures, vehicles, and imaginative creations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;history-of-lego&#34;&gt;History of Lego&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded by Ole Kirk Christiansen in 1932, the LEGO Group initially crafted wooden toys in Denmark. With a humble start making wooden ducks and yo-yos, the company transitioned to plastic toys in 1947, setting the stage for its iconic future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Coaches</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/projects/human-coaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 16:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/projects/human-coaches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human Coaches is a family business that I run together with my mother. We help students to improve their learning skills and offer tutoring. We also analyze people&amp;rsquo;s personalities according to the Human Design System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can visit our website &lt;a href=&#34;https://humancoaches.de&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Timon. I&amp;rsquo;m a&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;life time learner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;work time software dev (or let&amp;rsquo;s say tinkerer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;free time self-announced philosopher (does thinking count already?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find me either &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/projects/&#34;&gt;working on projects&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/blog/&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/reads/&#34;&gt;reading&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://timonrieger.de/photos/&#34;&gt;photographing&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/timonrieger&#34;&gt;tweeting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get in touch, you can send me an email at contact@ and the domain of this site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;principles&#34;&gt;Principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://peps.python.org/pep-0020/#the-zen-of-python&#34;&gt;The Zen of Python&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;learning gives purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;freedom in any way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;emotions are power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;silence is unvaluable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;living means being&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-areas-of-interest&#34;&gt;Current Areas of Interest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;software&#34;&gt;Software&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I originally started with &lt;a href=&#34;https://python.org/&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and developed several web applications with &lt;a href=&#34;https://flask.palletsprojects.com/en/stable/&#34;&gt;Flask&lt;/a&gt;.
Although I really appreciate its simplicity and extensibility as a well-established micro web framework, it has its limitations.
Therefore, I am currently looking into to more flexible and advanced frameworks,
such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://litestar.dev/&#34;&gt;Litestar&lt;/a&gt; for the backend and &lt;a href=&#34;https://svelte.dev/&#34;&gt;Svelte&lt;/a&gt; for the frontend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photos</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/photos/</guid>
      <description>A collection of photos from around the world. Powered by Olympus. All rights reserved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reads</title>
      <link>https://timonrieger.de/reads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://timonrieger.de/reads/</guid>
      <description>Here you will find my latest and most valuable reads (updated daily at 11am UTC via Readwise API).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
